Finding Aid for Women of Color Task Force (University of Michigan) publications, 1982-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Women of Color Task Force (University of Michigan) publications 1982-2002
University of Michigan. Women of Color Task Force
0.5 linear feet
9787 Bimu B28 2
ABSTRACT
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor # 7517 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The publications are open without restriction.
In 1979, Jennie Partee of the University of Michigan Affirmative Action Office and Beulah Sanders of the School of Education began offering career workshops for minority women several times a year. The stated purpose of the workshops was "to provide employees who are women of color with skills and confidence to move upward within the organization, both for their own benefit and to benefit the university by creating a more truly diverse and therefore enriched work force" (Box 1, History folder, "The History of the Minority Women's Task Force"). The workshops were aimed at both professionals and nonprofessionals and focused on practical topics such as communication skills and job hunting. A minority women's group developed from these workshops, sponsored by the Affirmative Action Office, the Human Resource Development Office, and the Medical Campus Office of Training and Development.
In 1982 the group officially became the Minority Women's Task Force and in 1983 held its first annual all-day Minority Women's Career Conference, which included speakers as well as workshops. Very similar to the career workshops, the conference had the added objectives of promoting a network among minority women at the university, sharing information and raising consciousness on common issues, and increasing the visibility of minority women. Entirely planned by volunteers on the Task Force, the annual conference has become the main activity of the group. The conferences grew from eleven workshops and 200 participants in 1983 to 45 workshops and 701 participants in 1989. Nearly 1000 people attended the 1992 conference, which was sponsored by the Affirmative Action Office, Medical Campus Human Resource Development, the Office of Human Resource Development and the Office of Minority Affairs.
In 1984 the Task Force implemented the Partee-Sanders Scholarship Fund, in honor of its two founders. In 1986 an awards program was established to recognize outstanding university women in human relations, leadership, and distinguished service in the Task Force. That same year the group changed its name to the Women of Color Task Force (WCTF), both to avoid the negative connotations of the word "minority" and to emphasize that it was concerned with women of all ethnic minority groups. In 1990 the WCTF broadened its purview to include women not only on the Ann Arbor campus, but on the Dearborn and Flint campuses as well, and began including a separate program for men of color during its annual conference, hoping to foster a male counterpart to the Task Force.
The Women of Color Task Force Publications include directories, newsletters, programs, brochures, and announcements, annual reports, clippings, posters, press releases, and programs of the Women of Color Career Conference. The publications are organized into two series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Women of Color Task Force.; University of Michigan. Minority Women's Task Force.; Women of Color Career Conference.
Genre Terms:
Directories.; Newsletters.; Brochures.; Announcements.; Annual reports.; Clippings.; Posters.; Press releases.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains printed material published specifically by the Women of Color Task Force. These publications are defined as being widely distributed and may be published at regular intervals. They are arranged by genre of the publication. This series includes annual reports, brochures, and directories. The series also includes three issues of the newsletter Passages dating from 1995 to 1996. There are seven issues of the WCTF News covering the period from 1989 to 1992.
  - Annual Reports
    - 1986-1990, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Brochures, 1983, 1992-1993, 1996 and 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Directories, 1982-1988 and 1994 (Box 1)
  - Flyers (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Passages, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
    - WCTF News, 1989-1992 (Box 1)
  - Symposia
    - Fall symposium, 1988 (Box 1)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from subordinate offices, departments, programs and organizations within the Women of Color Task Force. These publications are arranged alphabetically by the creating sub-unit. This series includes an almost complete collection of programs from the Annual Career Conference dating from 1983 to 2002. These programs and other supporting publications describe the conference presentations and workshops. There are also newspaper clippings and conference press releases in this series.
  - Annual Career Conferences
    - Clippings, 1983-1992 and 1995 (Box 1)
    - Conference Press Releases, 1984 and 1988-1995 (Box 1)
    - Programs, 1983-2002, 15 folders (Box 1)